&gt;&gt; Hi everybody, I'm Nick
&gt;&gt; 大家好 我是 Nick
Porcino.
Porcino
I work in the Games Technologies
我在游戏技术团队
Team, and I'm here to talk to
工作 今天在这里我想谈谈
you today about taking your art
如何将你的艺术作品
from, all the way from Asset to
从最初的素材开始
Engine using Model I/O, so
通过 Model I/O 引入到引擎
welcome.
欢迎大家
So, I'd like to begin by
所以在最开始 我想
refreshing you what's Model I/O.
先帮大家回想一下 Model I/O 是什么
Model I/O is Apple's toolkit for
Model I/O 是 Apple 为
building pipelines.
构建管道设计的成套工具
You can import and export 3D
你们可以用它来导入或导出 3D
assets in a variety of industry
素材 包括多个行业的
standard file formats, such as
标准文件格式 例如
common ones like Wavefront OBJ
常见的 Wavefront OBJ
and more modern ones like
以及更现代点的 像是
Pixar's USD.
Pixar 的 USD
It represents geometry and
它可以描绘几何结构
materials, lighting, cameras,
材质 光线照相机
voxels as well as lights and all
三维像素化 灯光以及
kinds of other things.
各种其他的东西
It does data format conversions,
它也可以进行数据格式转换
so you can get your assets
这样不管你所拿到的素材
coming in whatever format
原始创作时是
they're originally authored in
什么格式
and you can conform them to
你都可以使它们符合
particular strides and layouts
特定的步幅和布局
that you might need for Metal.
以满足 Metal 的需求
And, there's a variety of
另外还有各种
processing tools and we'll
处理工具 我们
review them briefly at the end
在演讲最后会简要地
of the talk.
评价一下它们
So, this year, there's a bunch
今年我们对
of improvements in Model I/O.
Model I/O 做了很多改进
I'm going to refer you to the
这里我想向大家推荐
developer website to learn more
我们的开发人员网站 帮助大家了解更多
details, but just to give you a
为了让大家
taste of what's coming up.
大致了解接下来的内容
There's improvements to the
我们对导入器
importers.
做了改进
We've got lots of feedback from
我们得到过很多这样的反馈
people who've loaded one exotic
当他们加载了外部
file format or another and run
文件格式 他们就会遇到
into issues.
问题
We've corrected things as
我们已经根据需求进行了
needed.
修正
We've introduced support for
我们引入了对
skinned character animation.
蒙皮角色动画的支持
And that's going to, that's
这点稍后
going to come up in a bit.
会讲到
We're supporting blend shapes,
我们支持融合变形
so if you have a character with
如果你有一个角色的两种表情
a say a smile and a frown, you
微笑以及皱眉
can go from one to the other
利用这个数据结构
with this data structure.
你可以实现两个表情间的转换
And we've got transform stacks
并且我们还有变换栈
which correspond to how data
对应数据在不同
looks in a program like for
程序中的状态 例如
example Maya where the animation
在 Maya 中动画将被
is going to be separated out
分为
into rotations and skills and
旋转 技巧
translations and put in certain
翻译 并以特定
orders.
的顺序摆放
Last year, we just gave you a
去年我们给了大家一个
matrix, this year we can compose
矩阵 今年我们能用
the components of the animation
你们在创作工具时用的
just the same as you do in an
同样的构件组成
authoring tool.
动画
Now, most importantly, Model I/O
现在最重要的是 Model I/O
gives you a consistent view on
能够让你们对你们的数据有
your data.
统一的视图
So, if you open up an asset, no
所以如果你打开一个素材
matter what format it was
不管它原本是什么格式
originally, Model I/O is going
Model I/O 将
to normalize it so that as you
对它进行标准化 这样你就可以
traverse it, you can write one
遍历它 写一个
loop of code, it's going to know
代码环 它将知道
how to go through all of the
如何每次以统一的方式
data in a consistent way every
处理所有的数据
time and for every asset that
对你加载的每一项素材
you ever load.
都是如此
So, this particular asset that
这个我放到屏幕
I've got up here on the screen
上的素材
is just a simple thing with a
只是车的一个小
car.
部件
It's got a camera, it's got a
它有一个摄像头 还有
light.
光
The car is broken down into
这辆车被分解为
components.
各种部件
It's got materials.
它有各种不同的材质
No matter what scene I load up,
不管我加载的是何种场景
it's going to come in like this
它都将是这样的
and it's going to be easy to
并且它非常容易
traverse.
遍历
So, that's why Model I/O is
这也是为什么 Model I/O
really easy and helpful in
真的非常容易使用 并且在管道中
pipelines.
非常有用
Now, we want to make something
现在 我们想创造
that looks like this.
像这样的东西
So it's going to be my little
这将是我的一个小
game.
游戏
And, the game is going to be
这个游戏将由
composed of art assets that were
一些艺术素材组成 它们
prepared in another tool like
已经在另外一个工具中准备好了
Maya for example or Blender or
这个工具可以是 Maya Blender 或者
whatever you like.
任何其他你喜欢的工具
And there's going to be models.
然后还需要有模型
There's going to be materials on
需要有模型上的
those models.
材料
There's going to be animations,
将有动画
textures of various sorts.
各种各样的纹理
And we're going to put a scene
我们将会从各种
together from a lot of different
不同的文件中整合
files.
一个场景
Now, when an artist creates an
一个艺术家在创造
asset, they're in a pretty
素材时 他们处于一个特别
sophisticated environment with a
复杂的环境中
lot of tools at their disposal.
有很多他们可以使用的工具
So, for an artist the art and
对于艺术家来说 艺术作品以及
the tool like Maya or Blender is
Maya 和 Blender 这些工具的意义
very much like source code for a
就像源代码
programmer.
对于程序员的意义
It's got all kinds of things
它有各种各样
that are super helpful for
对迭代和开发
iteration and development, but
非常有用的东西 但是
that don't actually make it into
那些并不能让它被运用到
the runtime.
运行中
You don't ship your code you
你们不需要交付代码 你们
ship your object code.
要交付的是编译代码
So, just like you compile source
正如你们在应用程序中
for your object code in your
为你们的对象编写
application, we're going to
源一样 我们将
compile assets to be optimal for
编写适用于引擎的
an engine.
最佳素材
Now, it's pretty tempting to
现在 制作基于 UI 的小工具
make nice little UI-based tool.
是非常有吸引力的
So maybe some Drag and Drop, and
所以也许通过一些拖放 以及
lots of things to click and
很多其他的操作去点击
slide around and so on and so
滑动等
forth, and it's going to be fun
去构造那个工具
to build that tool and it's
这个过程将会很有意思
going to be fun to use the first
而且最初使用的几次
few times.
也会很有意思
But then, I did my first car,
但是当我完成我的第一辆车
and then the artist gave me 12
艺术家又给了我另外 12 辆
more cars, and it's like really,
车的时候 那么
I have to drag all of them in,
我就必须把他们都拖进来
and I have to click all of those
一次又一次地去重复
buttons again and again and
点击同样的
again?
按钮吗
That kind of a tool becomes
那样这个工具很快就会变得
overwhelming pretty quickly.
让人非常有负担
What we're going to talk about
这里我们要讲讲
is how to scale that work using
如何通过管道批量处理
a pipeline.
这个操作
So, we're going to start with
我们将从图案
the artwork.
开始
We're going to use an exporter
我将使用一个导出器
to turn it into an asset.
将它转换为素材
We're going to use Model I/O to
我们将使用 Model I/O 将
transform that asset into
这个素材转换为
engine-ready data.
引擎就绪数据
We're going to load that
我们将在我们的引擎里
engine-ready data into our
加载这个引擎就绪
engine.
数据
We're going to convert it into
我们将把它转换为
Metal buffers and then we're
Metal 缓冲文件 然后 Metal
going to make a pretty picture.
将制作一张好看的图片
So, the very first step is to
所以第一步是
export the art.
导出艺术作品
Now, in the example that we've
在我们的
put together, we're using Maya
这个例子中 我们使用的是 Maya
and we have a little Python
我们有一个 Python
script that goes through Maya,
脚本 它将浏览 Maya
finds all the things.
找到所有的东西
It traverses complex hierarchies
它遍历复杂的层级
and files and it exports an
和文件 然后导出一个
asset file.
素材文件
Now, as I mentioned before, the
正如我之前提到的
choice of file formats is pretty
选择文件格式非常
important, and we're not going
重要 我们不会
to use something that's, you
使用齿轮处
know, a bit long in the tooth
有点长的东西
like Wavefront OBJ, we're going
例如 Wavefront OBJ 我们将
to use something fresh and
使用比较新的
modern which is Pixar's
现代的东西 也就是 Pixar 的
Universal Scene Description file
USD 文件
format.
格式
Now, I'm just going to say a few
现在我们要简要
words about it and first of all,
介绍一下它 首先
there is a website.
它有一个网站
You can see the URL there.
你可以在那儿看到网址
And you can find out all the
在这里你可以找到
details and information that you
你可能想知道的关于
possibly want to know about USD
USD 的细节和各种
there.
信息
Now, Pixar's Universal Scene
现在可以在他们的网站上
Description file format has been
找到 Pixar 的 USD 文件格式
in use at their site for years
这些文件多年以来用于
in the production of feature
制作动画
animation film.
长片
And as you know, or you might
大家可能还
recall from last year's SceneKit
记得在去年的 SceneKit
presentation, we integrated
展示 我们把
Universal Scene Description into
USD 整合到
the operating system, iOS and on
iOS 和 macOS
macOS last year.
操作系统当中
And we've been working with
我们一直在和
Pixar to improve that
Pixar 共同努力以不断改善
integration over time and add
整合情况 并且添加了
new features.
新的功能
Now, what makes Universal Scene
那么是什么让 USD
Description like super powerful
变得比之前所有的
compared to what we might have
都更强大呢
had before is the fact that we
正是因为我们
can take a whole ton of files
把大量的文件
and we can compose them together
组合在一起
to make a complex scene.
创造一个复杂的场景
So, in this particular sample
在这个样本里
here, I've decomposed the pieces
我从我们的赛道里面
from our race track, or from our
拆出了一些部件 或者从我们
game with a race track, into the
有赛道的游戏里面 然后把它们运用到
building, the race track, a tire
建筑物 赛道 轮胎
wall, a car, and some wheels.
墙壁 车辆以及一些轮子中
We're hierarchically composing
我们逐级将这些
that all together into a single
组合成一个单独的
file.
文件
And, just like that diagram I
正如我之前给你们看的
showed earlier where Model I/O
那张表格 Model I/O
will read everything in into
将把一切都解读为
easy to traverse format, that's
容易遍历的格式
what we're going to get when we
当我们只要将文件加载到
load this file into Model I/O.
Model I/O 中就可以实现这点
Now, the other great thing,
还有一件特别棒的事
another great thing you get from
另外一个你们可以从
Universal Scene Description is
USD 中得到的特别棒的东西
this idea of variations.
就是变化的概念
So, this is a really powerful
这对艺术家来说是一个
tool for artists to use when
非常强大的工具
they're putting a scene
他们可以用它来创造
together.
场景
If I want to have lots of cars
如果你希望跑道上
on that race track, what I can
有很多车 我可以用
do with USD is make a single car
USD 做的就是先做一个汽车
file, and I can have some
文件 然后我可以获得
shading variations.
各种颜色的变化
You can see them here, yellow,
大家可以看到这里有黄色的
green, red.
绿色的 红色的
And modeling variations, with a
还有各种模型的变化
fin and not with a fin.
有翼片的和没有翼片的
So, I can reference them into
我可以在文件里引用它们
the file, pick which versions
选择我所需要的
that I want, and then Model I/O
版本 然后 Model I/O
will essentially flatten that
将会对它们进行平面化
all down so that when you're
这样当你在
traversing the data structures
遍历数据结构
and looking to the data to make
寻找你的
your buffers, it's going to find
缓冲数据时 它将为你
the right things for you.
找到合适的东西
And I also want to mention that
我还想提到的一点是
Universal Scene Description has
USD 有
a ASCII format and a fast binary
ASCII 格式以及一个快速的二进制
format.
格式
So, the mesh with all of the
网格由成千上万的
thousands of vertices, normals,
顶点和法线等组成
and so on, I'm going to export
我将把它输出为
as binary.
二进制
But on the other hand, if I want
但是另一方面 如果我只是
to just noodle around with the
随机地使用这个
data, I can write text that
数据 我可以写一个
looks like this, where here I've
像这样的文本 这里我
got a world with an animation on
有一个有关
a car and the car is referenced
一辆车的动画世界 这个车将被引用
and I'm actually changing just
我只是改变了
the color on this car, and I put
这辆车的颜色 并且我把它放在
it in the animation scene, and
动画场景中
it's not animated by, you know,
大家知道它并不是根据它的
it's general principle here.
通用规则来进行动画绘制的
And this is really powerful for
这点对
just making variations and
创造变化和
iterating your assets offline
离线试验迭代素材来说
experimenting.
具有十分强大的功能
So, what we're going to build is
我们将构建的是
a little tool that's going to
一个小的工具 它将
take that Universal Scene
把 USD
Description asset and turn it
素材转化为
into engine-ready data.
引擎就绪的数据
So, command line tool.
命令行工具
The thing that we're going to
拥有命令行工具
get form having a command line
可以给我们带来的
tool is that it's going to be
好处就是
repeatable.
可复制性
It's repeatable because it's got
它可复制是因为具有
command line arguments.
命令行参数
The operation of tools can be
这些工具的操作可以保持
consistent because we've got
一致因为我们有
well defined inputs and outputs
定义良好的输入和输出
and parameters.
以及参数
It's going to be scriptable.
它将可编写脚本
So, you can batch your tools,
你可以分批处理你的工具
you can sequence your tools.
将你的工具排好顺序
It's going to give us the
它将给我们带来
scalability that we didn't have
可扩展性 这是
with the graphical user
图形用户
interface tool, and because we
界面工具所没有的 因为我们
can have automation without
可以不中断地进行
intervention.
自动操作
For example, the artist might
例如 艺术家可能
have a Dropbox folder somewhere,
在某处有一个 Dropbox 文件
where they're just going to
他们会把
throw all of their assets in
所有的素材都放进去
whenever they're ready to be
无论何时 只要他们准备好将它们整合进
integrated into the engine, we
引擎 我们
can have a little script
都可以用一个小脚本
monitoring that directory.
对该目录进行监测
Whenever it notices there's new
任何时候当它注意到有新
files, the processes that we're
文件时 我们将要介绍的
going to talk about in a moment
处理器
can automatically run, make it
将自动运行 使文件
engine-ready, and then move it
引擎就绪 然后移动它
so that when you build in Xcode,
这样当你们构建 Xcode 时
all the assets will be
所有的素材将被
automatically imported and ready
自动导入
for your game.
为你们的游戏做好准备
And finally, this kind of tool
最后 这种工具
is composable, and that's what
是可组合的 这正是
the little arc on the right side
表格右边的小弧线
of the diagram indicates.
所表明的
It's composable in the sense
如果我们的场景中有多个工具
that if I've got multiple tools
它是可组合的
and they can all read and write
它们都可以读写
the same blocks of data, then I
同样的数据块 然后我就
can feed one tool into another.
可以将一个工具送进另外一个中
I might do one tool and to
我可以用一个工具来
extract all the meshes and light
提取所有的网格 然后对它们进行
map them.
光照贴图
I might do another tool to find
我可能做另外一个工具来寻找
all the textures and make a list
所有的纹理 然后做一个
of textures.
纹理清单
And I make lots of little tools
我做了很多像这样的小工具
like that and put them together
然后把他们一起放进
into a workflow.
工作流程中
So, in this sample, it's a very
所以 这个样本
simple one.
还是非常简单的
And it doesn't go into a whole
它并不像很多其他的
lot of you know best practices
最佳实践
but it does give you a
它只是为了给大家
simplified data format that's
一个简化的数据格式
really easy to understand so
让大家更容易理解
that you can match what we're
这样大家便可以将
talking about versus what you
我们所讲的与你们
see in the code.
在代码中所看到的相匹配
There's no compression because
其中并没有压缩 因为
you don't want to obscure
你们不会想模糊
anything about what's going on.
正在进行的操作
This thing's intended to be a
它的目的是成为你们
jumping off point for you to
开始构建你们自己的
start to build your own pipeline
管道工具的起点
tools and elaborate them to
用它们匹配
match your own engines and data
你们自己的引擎和数据
formats.
格式
So, also like to talk a little
我还想谈一点
bit about the toy engine that
有关我们组合在一起的
we're going to put together.
玩具引擎
It's got a really simple
它内部有一个非常简单的
renderer in it.
渲染程序
It's all written in Swift and
它都是用 Swift 和
Metal.
Metal 编写的
It's a single-pass forward
它是一个单通道的
renderer, physically-based
渲染程序 基于实物的
shader, mesh instancing, skinned
着色器 对象副本 蒙皮
and animated meshes, multiple
骨骼动画以及多种
materials.
材质
Ticking off lots of bullet
那里标出了好多
points there.
要点
It's got a straight forward
它有一个非常直接的
rendering loop.
渲染循环
We have on the left side of the
在左边我们有
diagram, some meshes to draw.
那个表格以及一些需要绘制的网格
For everything that we want to
对于我们想画的所有事物
draw, we're going to set
我们都会设置
transform buffer, skinning data,
转换缓冲 蒙皮数据
vertex buffers, set our pipeline
顶点缓冲 设置我们的管道
state, material uniforms,
状态 材质均一
fragment textures.
以及碎片纹理
And we're going to draw indexed
我们将会为制作
primitive to make the pretty
好看的画面而绘制
picture.
索引的原语
So, we're going to call that
我们把那个工具叫作
tool the baker.
baker
So what are we going to bake?
那么我们要烤什么呢
We're going to bake, first of
首先 我们要烤
all, geometry and
几何结构和
transformations, what something
变换 事物的
looks like and where it sits.
样子 其所在位置
Texture paths and materials so
纹理路径以及材质
that when we're drawing those
这样在我们绘制那些
somethings we know what they're
东西的时候 我们知道
going to look like.
它们将呈现的样子
Instancing data so if we have
实例化数据 这样当我们有
say more than wheel, we're going
多个轮子的时候 将
to have information that tells
有信息可以告诉
us where to put many copies of
我们如何高效地将那个轮子的
that wheel in an efficient way.
多个副本放在何处
Transform animation, so that
转换动画 这样就
things can be animated.
可以让事物进行动画化
And finally, we're going to talk
最后我们将谈一下
about skinning and character
蒙皮和角色
animation.
动画
So, first of all, geometry and
首先是几何机构和
transformations.
转换
Now, from basic computer
了解基本计算机
graphics you're probably
绘图的话 你应该
familiar with a scene graph.
熟悉场景图
We've got a transformational
这里我们有一个转换
hierarchy here.
层级
A couple of transform nodes A
有转换节点 A
and B.
和 B
And A is perhaps a world's node
A 可能是一个世界节点
and maybe it doesn't provide
它可能只是提供
anything but an identity
一个恒等
transformation.
变换
B is a transformation that says
B 是一个转换节点 它说明
where is the car in the world.
了车在世界中所处的位置
And my racing car as one wheel,
我的赛车现在只有一个轮子
pretend you can see all the
假装你们可以在
other wheels off the bottom of
我的幻灯片下面看到
my slide here.
其他的轮子
And we've got a body.
我们还有车身
So, the way a transform
转换层级工作的方式是
hierarchy works is if I move the
如果我移动了
parent node everything
母节点 那个母节点
underneath that parent node
下面的一切
moves together as a unit.
都会作为整体一起移动
So, what we want to do is we
我们想做的是
want to get that information
要把那个信息放入
into our engine so that it can
我们的引擎中 这样它
render it ultimately.
马上就可以对其进行渲染
So we want to compactly encode
我们希望简洁地进行编码
that in a way that's easy to
使操作容易
store and easy to read and
存储并且
doesn't require me to fix up
不需要我去修复
pointers or any of that kind of
指示器或者任何其他的
thing.
此类事物
So, what I'm going to do is I'm
我将要做的是
going to flatten and
平面化
linearalize, linearalize that
并且直线化那个
array.
队列
I hope I don't have to say that
我希望我不需要再说
word again.
那个单词了
So, we're going to make an array
我们将进行一队列的
of local transformations.
本地转换
So the first one A is probably
第一个可能是
identity, the world, world
世界
matrix.
矩阵
Then another matrix to tell us
然后有另外一个矩阵告诉我们
where is the car.
车的位置
Another matrix to tell me where
另外一个矩阵告诉我
is the, the wheel.
轮子在哪里
is the car's body.
车身在哪里
I'm going to assign indices
我将分配指标
because those are going to be
因为稍后它们将会
really useful in a moment.
非常有用
So, 0, 1, 2, 3 that was the
0 1 2 3 将是
in-order traversal of the scene
场景图的
graph.
中序遍历
Now, I'm going to encode the
现在我将对那棵树
tree.
进行编码
So, I'm going to make another
我将编写另外
array of parent indices.
一队列母指标
The first entry is nil.
第一条是 nil
The world has no parent.
这个世界没有亲项
The car's root B has a parent at
这辆车的 root B 的亲项在
index 0, which is the world.
索引 0 中 也就是世界
The wheel is parented under the
轮子的亲项在
B, transfer node, as would the
B 转换节点下 其他的
other wheels be.
轮子也将是如此
The body is also parented under
车身的亲项也在
that node.
那个节点之下
So, we've encoded a graph.
所以我们编码了一个图表
Finally, we're going to want to
最后我们希望能够
be able to tell the engine what
告诉引擎需要
to draw, so we're going to draw
绘制什么 所以我们将绘制
a wheel, which is at index 2.
一个轮子 它在索引 2 下面
And we're going to draw the body
然后我们将绘制在
which is at index 3.
索引 3 的车身
So, we've described our scene in
我们用特别容易
a way that's really easy to
编写的方式描述了
write out.
我们的场景
And now, we also just need to
现在我们也只需要
tell what to draw.
描述需要画的内容
So, that's going to be a vertex
这将是一个顶点
descriptor, which is an array
描述符 也就是将
that's going to tell Metal these
告诉 Metal 以下信息的队列
are normals, these are texture
这些是标准的 这些是纹理
coordinates, these are
坐标 这些是
positions, the actual vertex
位置 真正的顶点可以
buffers themselves.
自行缓冲
And then the index buffer that
然后索引缓冲器
just says, you know, these
会表明这些
indices correspond to these
指数对应
triangles in the vertex buffers.
这些顶点缓冲区里的三角形
So, it's really easy to do this
有了我们一致的
with our consistent data
数据结构 是很容易
structures.
做到这点的
We're going to run through all
我们会把所有的对象
of the objects in the MDLAsset
放在 MDLAsset 对象里运行一遍
object after we've imported it.
在我们导入它之后
If the object can be casted to
如果对象可以被放入
MDLMesh, we're going to fetch
MDLMesh 里面铸造 我们将拿出 MDLMesh
out the vertexDescriptor which
以及顶点描述符 它将
tells us that we've got
告诉我们是否获得
positions and normalcy.
位置及正常状态
For all of the vertex buffers,
对于在网格里的所有
that are in that mesh, we're
顶点缓冲区 我们
just going to create an NSData
将根据顶点缓冲区和
from the vertex buffer bytes and
其长度创建 NSData
how long it is, and the dot dot
点点点
dot just tells us that we're
会告诉我们要
going to store that NSData
把 NSData 存储在
somewhere for encoding.
某处供编码使用
Then, we're going run through
然后我们将在
the submeshes and just a quick
子网格中运行 这里要快速
note about what is submesh.
介绍一下什么是子网格
And since I've just introduced
因为我刚刚提到了
that word, if we just think
这个词 我们可以想想
about that wheel, the wheel had
轮子 轮子有
a rubber tire and a metal rim,
一个橡胶轮胎和一个金属圈
right?
对吧
So, we're probably going to have
所以我们可能将有
two materials and therefore two
两种材质 所以需要有两种
draw calls.
绘制调用
But it's one mesh.
但是它还是一个网格
There are going to share a lot
他们将共用很多
of vertices, like on the
顶点 例如
intersection between the tire
轮胎和金属圈之间的
and the rim.
交叉点
So, we're going to make two
所以我们将创建两个
submeshes to just index the rim
子网格用来索引金属圈
and the tire with their own
以及轮胎 他们都有自己
independent index buffers and
独立的索引缓冲器和
meshes.
网格
So, we run through them, we cast
我们将运行它们 然后
them.
铸造它们
If we successfully cast them, we
如果我们成功地铸造了它们 我们就
create some NSDatas and stash
创建了一些 NSData
them for storage.
并且可以将之存储起来
Finally, for all of the objects
最后对于素材里面的所有
in the asset, we're just going
对象 我们将
to find if there's a transform
发现对象是否进行过
on the object, then grab its
变换 然后拿到它的
matrix and store it in the
矩阵 然后把它存在
array.
队列中
Well NSEncode and archive it,
完善 NSEncode 并将之归档
and these are the buffers that
这些是将
are going to go off to the disc.
进入光盘中的缓冲器
And the mesh data, descriptors,
网格数据 描述符
vertex and index buffers, the
顶点以及索引缓冲器
scene data which is the
对场景中参数
linearalization of the indices
进行直线化后的
of the hierarchy, and finally
场景数据 最后
the transformation data the
关于在哪里放置
actual places to put those
这些东西的
things.
变换数据
Next, we're going to fetch out
接下来 我们将拿出
all of the material data.
所有的材质数据
So, for every submesh, we're
对于每一个子网格 我们
going to find out that there's
将找出它
possibly a material.
可能对应一个材质
And if there's a material, we're
如果我们有一个材质 那么我们
going to find the parameters
将需要找到我们的着色器
that are needed by our shader.
所需要的指数
If our shader needs say diffuse
如果我们的着色器需要扩散
color and roughness, then we'll
色彩和粗糙度 那么我将
ask the MDLMaterial hey have you
问 MDLMaterial 你有
got those values, and then we're
哪些值 我将
going to check is it a scaler
确定它为定标
value or is texture and we're
值还是纹理 然后我们
grab that out and record it.
将拿出并且记录它们
Once again, the code's really
同样 这些代码都是非常
straightforward.
直接的
If the submesh has a material,
如果子网格有一种材质
run through all the properties.
它将在所有属性中运行一遍
What I'm not showing you here is
这里我没有向你们展示是因为
just filtering out the ones that
我只是为我们的运行时着色器
we actually care about for our
过滤出那些
run-time shader.
我们真正在意的东西
But once we've got to the point
但是一旦我们到了
of filtering it out, we're then
需要把它过滤掉的那个点
going to say, hey property are
我们将问 嗨 属性
you a string or URL?
你是字符串还是网址
If so, we're referring to a
如果是这样的话 我们将参考一个
texture and we'll just write out
纹理 然后我们直接
the texture path for later.
为之后编写出纹理通道
Otherwise we're going to check
不然我们就需要
and are you just a uniform
检查你是否只是一个统一
property like are you a float
属性 例如你是否是
value or a color or something
浮动值或者颜色或者
like that, and if that's what
类似的东西 如果是这样的
we've found then we'll write
那么我们将把它
that out.
写出来
And then once again, here's the
然后再次 这是我们
data that we wrote out in the
在之前的步骤里
previous step which was the
写出的数据 也就是
scene graph and the mesh.
场景图和网格
Now we'll write out the material
现在我将写出
uniforms and the texture paths.
材质均一和纹理通道
Finally, instancing.
最后进行实例化
So, this is where our car gets
也就是在这里我们的汽车
to have more than one wheel I
将有不只一个
think.
轮子
So, you're going to probably
你可能
want to use a single mesh more
想多次使用
than one time.
单一的网格
So, now my car has two wheels.
现在我的车有两个轮子了
Now, it's kind of a waste to
要把这个多次
store that in memory more than
存储在存储器里面
once, right?
有点浪费 对吧
It's the same wheel multiplied
它们都是同样的轮子
lots of times.
只不过重复了多次
So, Model I/O has a thing on the
所以 Model I/O 在
MDLAsset called a masters array.
MDLAsset 里有一个叫控制队列的东西
When you load one of Pixar's USD
当你加载一个通过实例化
files that uses instancing to
来复制数据的 Pixar USD 文件时
replicate data, Model I/O
Model I/O
notices that, collects all of
会注意到这点 并且收集
those replicated objects into
所有复制对象 把它们放入
the masters array, and instead
控制队列中 而不是
of storing the individual meshes
存储在单个的网格
in the nodes, instead just refer
的节点中 相反只是引用
it, just stores an MDLObject
它 只需要存储引用回
that refers back to the master
控制队列的
array.
MDLObjective 就行
And so that's how we get reuse.
我们就是这么做到重复利用的
And since Metal has great
而且 由于 Metal 有非常棒的
instancing facilities, that's
实例化设备 这将
going to stand us in good stead.
对我们非常有益
So, once again, we're going to
我们将再次
flatten the hierarchy and
平面化各个层级 并且
linearalize the arrays, just as
直线化队列
we did before.
和我们之前做的一样
And now on the right, you can
现在在右侧 你可以
see I've got two wheels in that
看到我在索引 2 3 4
array at indexes 2, 3, and 4.
队列中有两个轮子
But we want to batch those
但是我们希望成批处理
things together, so let's just
那些东西 但是我们
go ahead and do that.
现在就要做这个
So, we've grouped the tires
我们把这些轮胎分组
together, and now we've got the
放在一起 现在我们在底部
body down on the bottom.
有了车身
So, we're just going to store a
我们只要再存储
tiny little bit more data, which
一点点数据 也就是
is the instance count.
实例计数
There's two wheels and one body.
现在有两个轮子和一个车身
Eventually they'll be four
最后它将有四个
wheels, trust me.
轮子的 相信我
So, we're going to get the data
我们将调出
that we stored out already
我们之前已经存储好的
earlier and to the scene
数据 再到场景
composition data, we're just
组成数据 我们将
going to add the instance count.
添加实例计数
And that's all it takes to get
我们做了这些就可以得到
an instanced scene with lots of
一个包含多种材质和对象的
materials and objects.
实例化场景
Now, with that I'd like to hand
接下来我希望交给
it off to Nicholas to show you
Nicholas 来向大家展示
how that's all starting to come
这些是如何从最开始
together.
再到组合到一起的
[ Applause ]
［掌声］
&gt;&gt; I'd like to show you how easy
&gt;&gt;我要向大家展示用 Model I/O
it is to take our assets and
可以多么容易地
turn them into engine-ready data
把我们的素材变换为
using Model I/O.
引擎就绪的数据
I have here two folders and in
我这里有两个文件夹
the first folder we have our art
第一个文件夹里有我们的艺术
assets.
素材
It contains animation data,
它包含了动画数据
cars, it has skinned animation,
汽车 采用了蒙皮动画的方式
it has a bunch of materials.
它还有一堆材质
So what we want to do is we want
所以我们想做的就是我们希望
to create a baker that takes
创建一个 baker
this data, turns it into engine
它可以把这个数据变为引擎
data, and puts it into this
数据 然后把它放在
second folder here.
第二个文件夹里
So, what we have here is our
这里我们有我们的
baker project and what we're
baker 项目 我们要做的
going to do is we're going to
就是我们要
slowly extend it to extract more
慢慢地把它扩展 以从这些
and more data out of those art
艺术素材中提取更多的
assets.
数据
So starting out with the
从最简单的开始
simplest, let's export the
让我们来导出
geometry and transforms.
几何结构和转换
To do that we're going to walk
为了做这点 我们将浏览
the scene graph hierarchy and
场景图分级并且
look for any object of MDLMesh
寻找任何是 MDLMesh 类型的
type.
对象
Then we're going to store the
然后我们将存储
vertexDescriptor, all the
顶点描述符 所有的
vertexBuffers, and then we're
顶点缓冲区 然后我们
going to iterate through all the
将迭代所有的
submeshes and grab the index
子网格并且拿到索引
buffers.
缓冲器
We're going to walk through the
我们将再一次浏览
scene graph once again, and this
场景图 这次
time we're going to look for any
我们要寻找的是所有
objects that have a transform
有转换组件的
component.
对象
If they do, then we simply store
如果有的话 我们只需要存储
the matrix.
矩阵就行
And that's all for the first
第一个例子
example.
就是这样
And so let's go ahead and run
让我们运行
this.
它
And you'll notice in that second
大家会注意到在第二个
folder we now have a new file
文件夹里 我们有一个新文档
and that's our engine-ready
这就是我们的引擎就绪
data.
数据
This second project here will be
这里的第二个项目将是
our engine and it's going to
我们的引擎 它将
read in that data and it's going
读取那个数据 并且
to render it.
对其进行渲染
So let's see what we have so
我们来看看现在的
far.
成果
So as you notice, we have two
你可能注意到 我们的
cars on a race track, but
一个赛道上有两辆车 但是
there's color.
还有颜色需要处理
So let's extend the baker to
那么让我们扩展 baker
also support materials.
让它也支持材质
So in addition to looking for
我们不需要寻找
the index buffers on the
子网格上的索引缓冲器
submesh, we're going to look to
我们需要看看
see if it has a material
它是否有一个材质
property.
属性
If it does, then there are five
如果有的话 那么就有五个
properties associated with the
和以下相关的属性
semantic baseColor, metallic,
语义 baseColor 金属材质的
roughness, bump, and
粗糙度 碰撞以及
ambientOcclusion that we care
ambientOcclusion 这些我们
about.
在意的东西
And when we read in the
并且当我们在属性里
property, we're going to iterate
读取到相关的东西 我们将迭代
through all the properties and
浏览所有的属性
checking the type.
并检查类型
If the type is of float or
如果类型是 float 或者
float3 we assume it's a uniform
float3 我们就可以假定它是均一的
and we're going to record that.
并且我们也将记录它
Otherwise, if it's a string or a
不然 如果它是字符串或网址
URL we're going to record the
我们将记录
texture paths.
纹理通道
So now, let's run this second
现在让我们来运行第二个
example and see what kind of
例子 看看我们可以在我们的
output we get in our engine.
引擎获得何种输出
So now we have a race track and
现在我没有一个赛道
two cars, but now with
两辆车 现在还有
materials.
材质
Let's further extend this and
我们进一步进行扩展
support instancing.
并支持实例化
So, before, we only considered
之前在浏览场景图时
meshes while traversing the
我们只考虑了
scene graph.
网格
But now, we want to consider all
现在我们想要考虑所有
meshes that live in the masters
在素材控制队列中
array of the asset.
的网格
So we walk through the masters,
所以我们浏览控制网格
collecting all objects that are
收集所有是 MDLMesh 类型的
of MDLMesh type and storing in
对象 然后像之前那样
just like we did before.
存储它
In addition, we also need to
并且 我们还需要
record all objects that refer to
记录所有控制网格
those masters.
引用的对象
And we can find that on the
这点我们可以在
instance property.
实例化属性中找到
We then, sort the instances by
然后我们可以按网格区分
mesh, and then grab the instance
实例 得出实例
count.
计数
And that's it.
这样就完成了
So, let's go ahead and run our
现在让我们再运行一下
scene again.
我们的场景
And now we have multiple cars,
现在我们有多辆车
rendering using instancing.
我们用实例化对它们进行渲染
Back to you Nick.
交回给你了 Nick
[ Applause ]
［掌声］
&gt;&gt; Next, we're going to talk
&gt;&gt;接下来 我们要讲一讲
about transform animation.
变换动画
So, transform animation is
变换动画是
transforms that vary over time.
随时间改变的变换
So, let's just consider our
现在让我们再考虑一下我们的
little simple scene graph again.
场景图
Now, I've got a car sitting on
现在 在起点线上我们有
the start line, and I'm just
一辆车 现在我想
going to want to do an animation
做这么一个动画
where maybe the body is going to
例如在车发动之前
wiggle a little a bit before it
车身稍微摆动
starts, and then the car is
一下 然后车再
going to drive away.
开走
So in order to accomplish that,
为了实现这个效果
I'm going to need to record some
我需要在车身节点 D
animation data on the body node
以及整个对象的
D and on the root transform of
根节点上录制
the whole object to move him
一些动画数据来把它
away, which is B.
移走 也就是节点 B
I'm going to record out
我将要记录
animation tracks for both of
两个节点的
those two nodes.
动画路径
And once again with Model I/O,
同样有了 Model I/O
that's really easy to do.
这点特别容易做到
As before, we run over all of
和之前一样 我们浏览所有的
the objects looking for the
对象 寻找
transform components, and when
变换组件
we find them we're going to be
当我们找到它们的时候 我们将
appending them.
对它们进行附加
But now we're going to do one
但是现在我们还需要做
more thing, which is, we're
一件事 那就是我们将
going to ask the transform if
询问变换它是否
it's got any keyed times on it.
有键控时间
Now, if there's no keyed time,
如果没有键控时间
that's 0 count, then we're just
那么计数为 0 我们
going to use it as is.
直接使用就行
And if there's 1 keyed time,
如果有 1 个键控时间
we're just going to treat it as
我将把它看做
constant.
恒定
So we're just looking for counts
所以我们只需要寻找计数
that are greater than 1.
大于 1 的就行
So, we're going to actually use
我们现在要真正使用
a really exotic and cool piece
Swift 一个非常不同寻常
of Swift here.
非常酷的部分
I like this part.
我喜欢这个部分
We're going to use a map
我们将使用地图
closure.
闭合
So, what we're going to do is
我们将做的是
we're going to sample the
根据时间对
animation at times and we're
动画进行取样
going to create a new array of
我们将创建
transforms corresponding to
与那些时间对应的
those times that will append to
新队列的变换 并将之
our buffer.
附加在我们的缓冲器上
And to just pick apart that
现在把绘图操作
mapping operation a little bit,
拆开一下
the first line says
第一行说的是
samplesTimes.map.
samplesTimes.map
The thing that's not showing on
幻灯片上没有
the slide is where did
显示的是 sampleTimes
sampleTimes come from?
从哪里来
So, it's another array of
这是另外一个队列的
keyTimes and you can do two
keyTimes 你在这里
things here.
可以做两件事情
One is you can make the
一件事是你让
sampleTimes array just the
sampleTimes 队列就是
transform.keyTimes array, or if
transform.keyTimes 队列 或者如果
you want to instead of just
相反你只是想要
getting only the times that the
艺术家放进文件
artist put in the file, if you
中的时间点 例如如果
want to for example sample the
你想以恒定帧频
times at a constant frame rate,
对时间进行取样
you could have synthetically
你可以在你希望
made an array of transform times
的帧频下合成
at the frame rate that you care
一队列变换时间
about, say 60 frames a second.
例如 60 帧每秒
And so, when you do this mapping
所以当你在进行这个绘图
operation, the closure takes the
操作的时候 闭合进行了
transforms, gets the local
变换 在对应队列中
transform from it at the times
相应值的时间下
corresponding to the values in
获取本地
the array.
变换
I thought that was really cool.
我觉得这特别酷
So, here's the data that we've
这是我们已经导出
output already.
的数据
And it's straightforward to just
它非常直接地
encode the animated local
对本地变换动画
transforms.
进行了编码
So, finally, skinning and
最后蒙皮和
character animation.
角色动画
So, we're just going to take a
现在我们将要拿出一辆
little car here and he's a
小车 它
cartoon car apparently.
很明显是一辆卡通车
We're going to make him able to
我们将让它可以
wiggle his nose and otherwise
扭动它的鼻子 或者
animate.
做其他动画效果
So, as we've seen before, the
正如我们之前所看到的
mesh is going to have geometry
网格将有几何结构
and all the same sorts of
以及其他类似的
buffers and things that we've
我们之前谈论过的
already talked about, but it has
缓冲器 但是它还有
a new thing which is an embedded
一个被嵌入骨架的
skeleton.
新东西
I hope you can see the little
我希望大家可以看到这个小小的
green bones.
绿色的骨头
They are going out into the
它们将被放置在
wheels and there's some going
轮子中 在下面车的
down the spine of the car.
“脊柱”位置也有一些
Now, those bones are bound to
那些骨头通过
the vertices through a painting
艺术家们的绘画步骤
process that the artists do.
和顶点绑定
So, the one on the left has got
所以左边的有
a bone that's bound to the front
一根骨头和车的前部
of the car and heavily weighted
绑定 靠保险杠
to the bumper and the nose.
还有鼻子承重
And then the one on the right
然后在右边
we've selected one of the bones
我们选择了在车身背部
on the back of the car connected
的一根骨头和
to the wheel, so when that one
轮子相连 所以当这根
moves it's going to affect the
骨头移动时 它将影响到
wing on the back of the car and
车身背部的翼片以及
that wheel.
那个轮子
So, I should also mention that
我还需要提一下
that kind of data requires a
这种数据需要
little bit of extra work in your
你在你的着色器中多做一点
shader.
工作
We've got some more information
我们还需要一些信息
coming along for the ride that
为我们之前还没有做过的
we didn't have before.
发车做准备
And specifically, we've got the
特别是 我们有
jointWeights per vertex and the
jointWeights per vertex 以及
jointIndices which are a small
jointIndices 也就是一小
array of indices to what we'll
队列指数 我们将向
call the matrix palette of
它们调用和顶点位置
joints that correspond to the
相对应节点的
vertex positions.
矩阵调色
So, if two joints or bones were
如果有两个节点或者骨头
influencing a particular vertex,
同时作用于一个特定顶点
then the indices of those bones
那么当我进行变换时
will come along with the vertex,
那些骨头的指数将
with some weights so that when I
和顶点一起再加上一些重量
transform them, when I transform
当我在着色器中
them in the shader it'll all be
对它们进行变换时 它们将
combined together and the vertex
全部被结合起来 顶点
will move to its final deformed
将移动到其最后的变形
position.
位置
So, there's more data involved
为了从正在进行的几何结构和
in order to encode the skeleton
其他变换中
separately from the geometry and
单独编码骨架
other transformations that are
我们还需要更多的
going on.
信息
And that's the skeleton down
那就是表格
there at the bottom of the
底部中的
diagram.
骨架
Let's just isolate it.
我们把它分隔开来
So, as we did before, we're
所以和我们之前所做的一样
going to traverse the graph and
我们将浏览绘图
assign indices according to
然后根据浏览顺序 0 1 2 3
traversal order 0, 1, 2, 3.
分配指数
We're going to encode the
我们将对骨架图中的
parents in the skeleton graph
亲项进行编码
just as we did for the geometry
和我们之前对几何图所做的
graph.
一样
And so, not going to go into
我不会再细讲
particularly how it works
它的工作原理
because it's exactly the same as
因为这和之前的
before.
完全一样
Now, we're also going to encode
现在我们需要对
for each of the bones that
每一根骨头进行编码
actually influences a vertex,
它们会真正影响到顶点
the index of that bone in the
层级中骨头的索引
hierarchy and the inverse bind
以及逆绑定
pose.
姿势
On the previous slide, with the
在之前的幻灯片中
shader there is a bit of math
提到着色器的部分有一些
there that referred to some sort
数学运算提到某种
of a palette matrix.
调色矩阵
The inverse bind pose is going
逆向绑定姿势
to be an extra bit of math that
将需要你用多一点的
you need in order to get the
数学运算来帮你把
vertices into the right space to
顶点放入右侧空间
be easily blended.
使之更容易混合
And I'd refer you to the sample
我将让大家看一个
for the details of that
例子 以了解变换的
transformation.
具体细节
We're going to go through each
我们将浏览它们中的
one of those and store those
每一项 然后把那些
matrices and indices.
矩阵和指数存储起来
And then finally, to make an
最后 做一个
animation clip, we're going to
动画片段 我们将
record the animation that
录制和动画片段中
corresponds to each one of those
每根骨头
bones in the clip.
对应的动画
So, in code it looks very much
所以从代码的角度
like what we've seen before.
它和我们之前看到的非常像
We're going to go through the
我们将浏览对象
object and find out if the
找到对象是否有
object has skin.
蒙皮
The skin, corresponding to the
蒙皮和骨架等
skeleton et cetera and is
相对应 是在
encoded in Model I/O's new
Model I/O 全新的
MDLSkinDeformerComponent.
MDLSkinDeformerComponent 中编码的
So if we found a skin deformer
所以如果我们发现一个蒙皮变形器
component, we're once again
组件 我们将再次
going to take advantage of this
利用
Swift map closure to take the
Swift 地图闭合 利用
jointBindTransforms that Model
Model I/O 从文件中读取
I/O read from the file and
并且存储的
stored.
jointBindTransforms
We're going to use this simd
我们将利用这个单指令
inverse to invert all of them
倒转来倒置它们
because that's what the math
因为数学运算需要
needs, and store it in an array.
将它存储在一个队列中
And then, here's all the data
然后这里是我们到现在为止
that we've stored to date.
存储的所有数据
And we're going to put out the
我们将调出
skeletal data, the inverse bind
骨架数据 逆向绑定
transforms, and the joint to
变换和色斑映射
palette mapping, and the
的连接点 以及
skeleton parent indices.
骨架亲项指数
And so, I'd like to ask Nicholas
我想请 Nicholas
to come up again and show us
再次上台来向我们展示一下
what it looks like now.
它现在的样子
[ Applause ]
［掌声］
&gt;&gt; So where we last left off, we
&gt;&gt;从我们上次的地方开始 我们
had a race track with multiple
有一个赛道 多辆
cars rendering using instancing.
汽车使用实例化进行渲染
Now, in addition let's also
现在我们再让它
support animation.
支持动画效果
So, before when we traversed the
之前在我们浏览
scene graph and we looked for
场景图的时候 我们寻找
any object that had a transform
任何有变换组件的
component, we assumed it was
对象 然后我们假定它是
constant.
恒定的
Now we want to know if the
现在我们希望知道
transform is time varying.
变换是否会随着时间而改变
And the easiest way to find that
找到这个答案的最简单的办法
out is to see if the
就是看看
keyTimes.count is greater than
keyTimes.count 是否大于
If it is, then for the purposes
如果是 为了达到
of this sample, we're going to
样本的目的 我们将
sample it in regular intervals.
在特定时间间隙取样
So, we sample them and then we
我们对它们进行取样
store them.
然后存储
And that's it for animation.
动画就是这样的
So, let's go ahead and run this
现在让我们来运行这个
example and see what kind of
例子 看看我们的引擎
output we get in our engine.
可以得到哪种输出
So, now you notice that the
大家注意到
front cars are taking off.
前面的车已经发动了
So, finally let's go ahead and
最后我们来
add in skinning.
加上蒙皮
Let's extend the baker to
现在让我们把 baker 扩展到
support skinning now.
支持蒙皮
So, in addition to any mesh data
所以你需要的除了有
that you may need, there's an
网格数据 还有
additional skin data that you
蒙皮数据
might need and so we check to
所以我们需要检查
see if a MDLMesh has a component
看看 MDLMesh 是否有
conforming to MDLSkinDeformer.
和 MDLSkinDeformer 一致的组件
If it does, then two bits of
如果有 那么我们
additional information we need
还需要两点额外信息
is we need to know how the
也就是我们需要知道
skeleton is bound to the skin
骨架如何和蒙皮网格绑定
mesh, and we need to know its
我们还需要知道
animation data.
动画数据
So, we find that paths of all
所以我们找到了 jointPaths 队列
the bound skeleton joints in the
中所有的绑定
jointPaths array.
骨架连接点
And then, we find the bind pose
然后我们找到
of the skeleton in the
jointBindTransforms 中的
jointBindTransforms.
骨架绑定姿势
So, now that we know what our
现在我们已经知道我们的
skeleton looks like, let's go
骨架长什么样子了 让我们
ahead and time sample the
继续根据时间对
skeleton's joints transforms
骨架连接点变换进行取样
just like we did objects local
和我们之前对本地对象
transform.
变换所做的一样
So we time sample it in regular
我们根据特定的时间间隔
intervals, store the matrix, and
进行取样 存储矩阵
then we decompose it into a
然后我们把它分解为
quaternion rotation,
四元数旋转
translation, and we store it in
翻译 然后把它存储在
an animation clip.
动画片段中
So, let's go ahead and run this
现在让我们来运行这个
example.
例子
So now we have a skinned car.
所以现在我们有了一辆蒙皮汽车
So, to recap on what we've done.
我再总结一下我们所做的
We were able to construct a
我们用 Model I/O 构建了
simple baker using Model I/O
一个简单的 baker
that exported geometry and
它可以导出几何结构和
transforms, and with a bit of
变换 再加点代码
code we were able to extend it
我们就可以对它进行扩展
to support, materials,
使它支持材质
instancing, animation, and
实例化 动画以及
skinned animation.
蒙皮动画
All 5 of these examples and the
这五个例子以及
engine are available for this
引擎都放在
session sample code which you
这个环节的代码样本中
can modify for your own engine's
大家可以根据自己的引擎需求进行
needs.
修改
Back to you Nick.
交回给你了 Nick
[ Applause ]
［掌声］
&gt;&gt; All right then.
&gt;&gt; 好的
So, quick recap.
快速总结一下
We've shown taking artwork all
我们展示了如何把图案
the way from your asset creation
从最初的素材创作
program to Pixar's Universal
程序变成 Pixar 的 USD
Scene Description file format.
文件格式
We used Model I/O to transform
我们运用 Model I/O 将
that asset into engine-ready
素材变换为引擎就绪
data and we encoded it and
数据 我们对它们进行编码
archived it off to the disc.
然后把它们在光盘中归档
We put together a little game
我们利用 Swift 和 Metal
engine with a simple renderer
进行了简单的渲染
using Swift and Metal.
制作了一个小游戏
And we loaded all that data up
我们加载了所有的数据
and we animated it and we drew
然后我们将它进行动画化 而且我们绘制了
some pretty pictures.
一些漂亮的画面
So, what's next?
那么接下来呢
Well, I'd encourage you to have
我会鼓励大家去
a look at the other facilities
看看 Model I/O
that Model I/O's got built into
内置的其他
it.
设备
There's a whole ton of tools
我们还有非常多其他工具
that are useful for building
可以帮助大家构建
your own tools.
自己的工具
Your own tools for that pipeline
你们自己的适用于管道链的
chain.
工具
For example, if you have a scene
例如 如果你有一个
composed of a bunch of objects,
由多个对象组成的场景
you can perform a light mapping
你可以进行一个光照映射
operation.
操作
Model I/O will cast lots of
Model I/O 可以制作多种
rays, it'll bounce light around.
射线 它将让光线四处跳动
It'll make a prioritization for
它会将场景作为
the scene, store the data all
优先事项 并且为你存储
out for you.
所有的数据
It's got tools to do things like
它还有可以做
UV unwrapping, so we've taken a
紫外线解相位的工具 我们有一个
little airplane and carved it
小的飞机 我们可以把它
apart into the logical chunks
分为小的逻辑块
that are ready for painting.
这样就易于绘图
It has other operations like
它还有其他的操作 例如
here we're calculating ambient
这里它可以计算环境光
occlusion.
遮蔽
So, we've taken the little
例如这个小
airplane, we've done ray casting
飞机 我们已经做了光线投射
to compute accessibility of the
来计算从外部
surface from the outside and
表面的可及性并
encoded that as a signal on the
进行编码
surface of the plane, so that
飞机表面有一个信号 那么
your shader can render an object
你的着色器对你场景中
to be more physically grounded
对象的渲染将会更接近
in your scene.
实景
Here's another fun thing that
这里还有一件
you can do.
你能做的有意思的事
We've got all kinds of tools for
我们有各种各样
dealing with 360-degree imagery,
处理 360 度图像的工具
which would be very helpful for
它们对于为 VR 等
like making panoramic spheres
制作全景图像
for VR and whatnot.
非常有用
So, on the very left there you
在最左边你们
can see a 360-degree picture
可以看到一张 360 度的图片
that was taken with you know one
它是用你们知道的那种
of those funny little cameras.
小相机拍摄的
And Model I/O can convert it to
Model I/O 可以将它转换为
a cube map ready for hardware.
可供硬件使用的立方体地图
It can also take a cube map and
它也可以把一个立方体地图
convert it back to that other
转换回为它另外一种
format.
格式
And then the two blurry columns
边上两个
down on the side are
模糊的栏
precomputing the irradiance
可以为你预计算
convolution for physically-based
基于实物着色的
shading for you.
辐照度卷积
So, we're creating a bunch of
我们制作了一些
coefficients that are ready for
系数可以为
your shader so that if we
你的着色器所用 这样如果我们
dropped an object into the scene
把一个对象放到场景中
it would feel physically
它将会找到它合适的
situated.
物理位置
So, there's all kinds of things
它里面有很多
like that in there.
类似的东西
And I encourage you to go off
希望大家可以自己去
and explore.
探索
So, as Nicholas mentioned, this
Nicolas 刚刚也提到
sample is available for download
样本在会议的网站上
on this session's website.
可以供大家下载
So, please go grab like the
所以希望大家能去用
little car and find the other,
那个小车的代码 或者找到其他的
you know, missing wheels.
例如那些消失的轮子
And, there's a bunch of other
另外还有其他的
sessions that are worth
有意思的环节
reviewing in order to learn more
大家可以按需要观看 以了解
about these topics.
有关这些话题的更多内容
There was Introducing Metal 2
其他环节有 “介绍 Metal 2”
and What's New in SceneKit and
“SceneKit 的新功能” 还有
I'd also refer you to the What's
一个我想向大家推荐的是去年大会的
New in SceneKit session last
“SceneKit 的新功能”
year when we went into some
在那里我们详细
details about the integration
介绍了与 USD 的
with USD.
融合
And from 2015 there was also the
2015 年的大会也有
introductory session on Model
介绍 Model I/O 的相关环节
I/O where we go into quite a lot
那里我们非常详细地
of detail about the various data
介绍了各种数据
structures and operations on
结构 以及在那些结构上的
those structures.
操作
So, with that.
那么 就到这里
Thanks for showing up and hope
感谢大家的聆听 希望
you enjoyed it.
你们喜欢
[ Applause ]
［掌声］